import { QuizQuestionList } from "../typings/quizTypes";

const CH_NUM = 1;

const questions: QuizQuestionList = [
  {
    question: "Living things _____.",
    options: [
      "respond to stimuli",
      "reproduce",
      "have adaptations",
      "all of the above",
    ],
    correctIndex: 3,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The smallest unit of matter that can enter into chemical combination is a _____.",
    options: ["cell", "atom", "molecule", "neutron"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "The smallest living unit is a _____.",
    options: ["cell", "atom", "molecule", "tissue"],
    correctIndex: 0,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "Similar cells with a similar function describes a _____.",
    options: ["organ", "population", "tissue", "organ system"],
    correctIndex: 2,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "All of the gray squirrels in a temperate deciduous forest are referred to as a _____.",
    options: ["community", "population", "ecosystem"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "Unicellular organisms cannot respond to their environment.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The ultimate source of energy for nearly all living things is _____.",
    options: ["fossil fuels", "the sun", "thermal vents", "water"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "Homeostasis is _____.",
    options: [
      "balancing internal and external conditions",
      "wild fluctuations in internal conditions",
      "the transformation of the sun's energy into organic molecules",
      "the maintenance of internal conditions within certain limits",
    ],
    correctIndex: 3,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "The ability to respond _____.",
    options: [
      "ensures survival of the organism",
      "allows the organism to carry on its daily activities",
      "all of the above",
    ],
    correctIndex: 2,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Only plants are able to capture solar energy and carry on photosynthesis.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "All cells have a copy of the hereditary material, DNA.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 0,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The instructions for the organization and metabolism of living things are encoded in the _____.",
    options: ["genes", "plasma membrane", "cell wall", "ribosomes"],
    correctIndex: 0,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Some organisms reproduce by simply splitting in two in a process called _____.",
    options: ["mitosis", "meiosis", "vegetative propogation", "binary fission"],
    correctIndex: 3,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "In most multicellular organisms, reproduction involves the pairing of a sperm from one partner and an egg from the other partner.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 0,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The characteristics of living things suggests that living things descended from several different ancestors.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "Hypotheses can be tested in _____.",
    options: [
      "laboratory experiments",
      "field experiments",
      "all of the above",
    ],
    correctIndex: 2,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "When a person uses isolated facts and creative thinking to arrive at an explanation for something, he/she used _____ reasoning.",
    options: ["inductive", "deductive"],
    correctIndex: 0,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Deductive reasoning begins with a general statement that implies a specific conclusion.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 0,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "A control group experiences all the steps in an experiment.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "The component in an experiment being tested is called the _____ variable.",
    options: ["control", "experimental", "dependent"],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "An experiment is done to see if eating breakfast affects students' performance on exams. The experimental variable is _____.",
    options: [
      "the students' scores on the exams",
      "the age of the student",
      "whether the student has breakfast or not",
      "whether the student drinks coffee or not",
    ],
    correctIndex: 2,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is an assumption scientists must accept when performing the scientific process?",
    options: [
      "natural laws are not affected by time",
      "nature is real, understandable, and knowable by observation",
      "nature is orderly and uniform",
      "all of the above",
    ],
    correctIndex: 3,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "Theories that are generally accepted by an overwhelming number of scientists are called _____.",
    options: ["principles", "laws", "both"],
    correctIndex: 2,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question: "The first step in the scientific method is _____.",
    options: [
      "make conclusions",
      "make observations and consider previous data",
      "formulate a hypothesis",
      "test a related hypothesis",
    ],
    correctIndex: 1,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "If an experiment is done to see if a dietary supplement affects the weight gain of chickens, what variables need to be controlled?",
    options: [
      "where the chickens are kept",
      "the availability of water",
      "the temperature of the surroundings",
      "all of the above",
    ],
    correctIndex: 3,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the research subjects are different, it is hoped that random selection distributes them equally among the groups.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    correctIndex: 0,
    chapter: CH_NUM,
  },
];

export default questions;
